Finding Aid for Central Michigan University. Multicultural Education Center Collection
Clarke Historical Library
Collection, 1987, 2011, and undated
Central Michigan University. Multicultural Education Center.
6.75 cubic feet (in 12 boxes)
MSS.
The collection documents the center's history with reports, newspaper clippings, photographic materials, and VHS videos.
Clarke Historical Library, Central Michigan University
Acc#72964, 73681
Central Michigan University. Multicultural Education Center Collection is open for research.
Organizational History:
The Central Michigan University Multicultural Education Center was established in 1987. It is one of several units on campus which falls under the aegis of The Office of Institutional Diversity, the others being Gear Up, Gay and Lesbian Programs, Minority Student Services, Native American Programs, and Upward Bound.
In 2011 the main goal of the CMU Multicultural Education Center was to help build an inclusive and respectful CMU community in a variety of ways. The Center provides a meeting place in general for students, for Registered Student Organizations (RSOs), and for various campus events including Soup and Substance, speak UP, Speak Out. The center functions as a resource center of videos, DVDs, and books, and recognizes all major religious and cultural holidays. It offers various exhibits throughout the year. The Center also provides professional development and workshop opportunities for CMU staff. (This information is from the collection.)
In August 2011, the name of the office changed to Office of Diversity Education. It was previously called the Multicultural Programming Center until 1999/2000. In 2012 it became the CMU. Multicultural Education Center.
Arrangement is alphabetical and then chronological, except Box 12 which is chronological.
The collection is organized by format into the following series: papers, mostly newspaper clippings (1 cubic ft.), photographic materials, mostly of exhibits (.5 cubic ft.), and VHS videos on a wide variety of topics (2 cubic ft.). Each series is then organized alphabetically and chronologically.
The papers consist mostly of newspaper clippings (copies), 1980s-2010, and undated as well as programmatic materials, minority equality reports, copies or original artwork, and the Center’s webpage (copies), 2011.
Photographic materials consists mostly of colored photographs as well as some negatives and contact prints, mostly documenting Center art exhibits or KCP (King / Chavez / Parks) Days or Workshops at CMU for minority students, 1993, 2008, and undated.
The VHS videos, 1987, 2006, and undated, document visiting speakers, panel discussions, soup and substance and breakfast discussions, and other events covering a wide variety of multicultural topics including Native Americans, Disabilities Act, Affirmative Action, African Americans, Ojibwa traditions, feminism, Speak, Speak Out, diversity, etc. A few are user copies of CMU media productions, CMU Minute and Editor’s Notepad. Native American topics are particularly well documented. There are also six videos covering parts 7-24 of Dealing with Diversity, 1993.
The Addition to the collection, 1981-2010, and undated, 2.75 cubic ft. (in 6 boxes) consists of the same formats and information as the original collection. Boxes 1-3 are alphabetical subject files with photographs. Boxes 4-5 are of special interest as they include correspondence, reports, and other materials relating to the Chippewa nickname used by CMU. Box 6 includes several videos and a cassette tape.
The July 2019 Addition includes Box 12 (.5 cu.ft.), 10 VHS color videotapes, 1984-1993: The Legal (Pre-Employment) Interview, 1984, an acted interview with illegal questions, copyright 1984 by CMU Office of Affirmative Action, 5 minutes 58 seconds. Handicappers Rights, 1988, Marshall Rose and the Mount Pleasant Committee on the Handicapped lead a small, inaugural discussion on accessibility, dignity and quality of life in an unidentified CMU class room, 1.5 hours. Cultural Diversity at CMU, [1988] which includes discussion of the CMU mascot, speakers Pres. Jakubauskas, Dr. Nancy Belck, Dr. Rebecca Torres-Riviera, Dr. Ulana Klymyshyn, produced by CMU Library Instructional Resources, 6 minutes 49 seconds. Sexual Issues in the University, 1989, Marshall Rose, the CMU Affirmative Action officer, leads a panel discussion of Dr. Megan Goodwin, Dr. Angela Haddad, and Dr. James Jones on the topic, 1 hour, 3 minutes, 29 seconds. Marshall Rose on Whites in Black History, 1989, a very informative, thoughtful, presentation, about 1 hour, tape is in very bad shape. Have We Finally Arrived at Educational Equity Forum, 1990, includes Dr. Rita Kissen Dr. Robert Levy, Dr. Barbara Kirk discussing race, ethnicity, how to train teachers, 1 hour 6 minutes 36 seconds, this video is in very bad shape. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Freedom March and Commemorative Program, 1991, march of CMU students and staff from Foust to Warriner, 2 banners of note-Eta Sigma Gamma supports the dream and Barnes Hall Taking the dream into the 90s, two unidentified African American male speakers and Leticia Gary (?) in front of Warriner, 11 minutes, 29 seconds. Affirmative Action Annual Think Take, Tape 1, 1991, sponsored by Kappa Alpha Psi by two African American poets, Dr. Kenneth Zakee, and Askia M. Toure, and a presentation by Miss Lefisa (sp?) in the Theatre on the Side, 2 hours 3 minutes 36 seconds. Affirmative Action Annual Think Take, Tape 2, 1991, continues Tape 1, 24 minutes, 25 seconds. Dr. Lloyd Elm, Lincoln Address, 1993, Onadago Tribe member and Native American educator presentation in UC at unidentified conference, 37 minutes, 4 seconds.
Due to shelving issues, the Addition boxes are shelved separately from the main collection.
Subjects:
Central Michigan University. Multicultural Education Center.; Central Michigan University. Office of Institutional Diversity.; Central Michigan University--History.; Multicultural education.; Art--Exhibitions--Michigan.; Art--Exhibitions--Mount Pleasant.; Affirmative action programs.; Indians of North America--History.; Minority college students.; College dropouts--Prevention.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.)--History.
- Central Michigan University. Multicultural Education Center Collection
  - Brochures,1988/1989, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence,2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fliers,1992-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graduation / Retention Improvement Program (GRIP),1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guest Book,1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies), Press Releases,1980s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies, folder 1 of 2),1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies, folder 2 of 2),1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings (copies),undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Office of Minority Equality, Michigan Department of Education, Reports,1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Office of Minority Equality, Michigan Department of Education, Reports,1992-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Original Artworks,2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Photographs and Negatives, Native American Event,undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, Jazz,1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, KCP (King / Chavez / Parks) College Day,1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, KCP College Day,1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, KCP Workshops,1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, KCP Workshops,1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Negatives, Contact Prints, KCP Workshops,1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, KCP Workshops,1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, New School Play,1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Latino Art and Artists,undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Native American Exhibits,1999, 2001, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs and Negatives, Powwow in Rose Arena,2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Powwows in Finch Fieldhouse,undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Powwows in Finch Fieldhouse,undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, President Plachta Retirement Party,2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Soup and Substance,1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Students, Ulana Klymyshyn; Quilts,2000, 2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, Web pages,2011 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - VHS Videos, #3 Ward Churchill at Central Michigan University “A Little Matter of Genocide…” (2 copies),November 12, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - VHS Videos, #4 Ghandi, Arun: at Central Michigan University, “A Non Violence,undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - VHS Videos, #15 Cheryl Gilkes: Afro American Women and the Sociology of W.E. B. DuBois,October 17, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - VHS Videos, #22 Eddie Benton-Banai, Anishinaabe in Y2K,” 7:30pm,November 2, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - VHS Videos, #23 Bell Curve Panel Presentation,undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - VHS Videos, #23 The Bell Curve Panel Discussion,undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - VHS Videos, #27 Breakfast with…Bell, Derrick, Activism, Community and the Permanence of Racism,April 15, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - VHS Videos, #28 Breakfast with…Kincaid, Jeanne, Americans with Disabilities Act,March 13, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - VHS Videos, #29 Breakfast with…Maestas, Ricardo, Building Communities,March, 21, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - VHS Videos, #30 Breakfast with…Pallone, Dave, Behind the Mask,February 24, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - VHS Videos, #31 Breakfast with…Wilkins, Roger, Affirming Affirmative Action, 1:01,December 6, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - VHS Videos, #32 Breakfast with…Anishnaabe Elders Discussing Current Events (2 copies),November 19, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - VHS Videos, #33 Breakfast with… Benton-Banai, Eddie, Meeting the Needs of Native American Students,undated [1999?] (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - VHS Videos, #34 Breakfast with…Cajete, Greg, “Philosophical Foundations of Indigenous Education”,January 30, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - VHS Videos, #36 Breakfast with…Churchill, Ward, “The Tragedy and the Travesty: The Subversion of Indigenous Sovereignty in North America”,November 12, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - VHS Videos, #37 Breakfast with…Renee Wasson Dillard,February 13, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - VHS Videos, #38 Breakfast with…Elm, Lloyd, Our Greatest Resource: Indian Traditions, 44:00,November 16, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - VHS Videos, #39 Breakfast with…Paula Ettelbrick, MASTER,September 24, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - VHS Videos, #40 Breakfast with…Fu, Victoria, In Search of Connection: Developing a Pedagogy of Caring, 1:06,April 12, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - VHS Videos, #41 Breakfast with…Gray, John, Creating Organizations that Value Diversity: Articulating a Pluralistic Vision,October 13, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - VHS Videos, #42 Breakfast with…Ginsberg, Margery, Culturally Responsive Teaching, 48:00,February 29, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - VHS Videos, #43 Breakfast with…Washington, Jamie, Beyond Tolerance: Multicultural Organizational Development,April 24, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - VHS Videos, #46 CMU Minute: “About the Multicultural Center and Its Purpose,1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - VHS Videos, #47 CMU Minute: CMU Powwow,1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - VHS Videos, #53 Dealing with Diversity parts 7, 8, and 9 11:00-14:00,May 18, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - VHS Videos, #54 Dealing with Diversity parts 10, 11, and 12, 14:00-17:00,May 18, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - VHS Videos, #55 Dealing with Diversity parts 13, 14, and 15, 11:00-14:00,May 19, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - VHS Videos, #56 Dealing with Diversity parts 16, 17, and 18, 14:00-17:00,May 19, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - VHS Videos, #57 Dealing with Diversity parts 19, 20, and 21, 11:00-14:00,May 20, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - VHS Videos, #58 Dealing with Diversity parts 22, 23, and 24, 14:00-17:00,May 20, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - VHS Videos, #61 Editor’s Notepad-Harvey Arden, Air Date,October 13, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - VHS Videos, #62 Kirwan, William, “Educational Excellence through Diversity,” MASTER,September 12, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - VHS Videos, #63 Song, Prof. Huang Ron: Eight Developmental Stages of Block Building in Young Children,May 11, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - VHS Videos, #68 Frank Cloutier (Tribal spokesman), On Editor’s Notepad [copy],April 1, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - VHS Videos, #73 (Keynote Address) Cajete, Dr. Greg “Indigenous Ways of Knowing: Practical Applications”,January 30, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - VHS Videos, #74 Central Michigan University, King / Chavez / Parks (KCP) Ojibwe Traditions Workshop (2 copies),1995 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - VHS Videos, #75 Central Michigan University, KCP (King / Chavez / Parks) Ojibwe Traditions Workshop (1 copy),1996 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - VHS Videos, #75 Central Michigan University, KCP (King / Chavez / Parks) Ojibwe Traditions Workshop (1 copy),1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - VHS Videos, #81 Herbert Martin,March 17, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - VHS Videos, #83 Multicultural Recruitment Video,Spring 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - VHS Videos, #86 “Muslims in America,” segment (30 minutes) Begins approximately 5 minutes into video,August 27, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - VHS Videos, #87 Giddings, Paula “National Association of Colored Women: Betwix and Between Booker T. and W.E.B. DuBois”,undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - VHS Videos, #91 Native American Month, Pub. SIP Video 2:15,undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - VHS Videos, #92 Ward Churchill, Go Chips: Fanning the Flames of Institutional Racism, 1:25,November 11, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - VHS Videos, #93 Native American Promo (PBS),undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - VHS Videos, #94 Native American Community Leadership Meeting,September 3, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - VHS Videos, #95 Dub for: Central Michigan University, Topic: Native Americans Part One,undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - VHS Videos, #96 Dub for: Central Michigan University, Topic: Native Americans Part Two,undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - VHS Videos, #98 New School,August 30, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - VHS Videos, #99 Ojibwe Traditions Banquet (2 copies),1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - VHS Videos, #100 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop,June 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - VHS Videos, #101 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop (2 copies),June 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - VHS Videos, #102 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop,1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - VHS Videos, #103 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop, Central Michigan University,June 1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - VHS Videos, #104 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop,July 24-30, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - VHS Videos, #105 Ojibwe Traditions Workshop,1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - VHS Videos, #108 Powwow Preview, Edited, 27:00,undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - VHS Videos, #114 Yvonne Woodward, Roots KCP,1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - VHS Videos, #116 Gloria Steinem, Central Michigan University,October 30, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - VHS Videos, #120 Falcusan, Jeff, "The Chippewa Nickname at C.M.U.",November 19, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - VHS Videos, #136 Ward Churchill - Editor's Notepad (2 copies),November 11, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - VHS Videos, #139 Speak Up, Speak Out,January 25, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, C.A.C.,1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, CCLO Orientation,2006 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Campus Climate Conference,1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Catalog of Diversity Recommendations,1981-1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Chippewa Educational Committee,undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Coalition in Defense of Equal Protection at CMU,1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Cultural Awareness Coalition,1989, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Cultural Diversity Administration Council,1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Cultural Diversity at CMU,1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity, Affirmative Action, and Hatchling Program at CMU,1989, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Brochures,1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Forum,2003 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Forum,2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Forum,2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Forum,2007 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity Incentive Grants and Awards,2007 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Diversity, Student Service Team,undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Equity Conference,2002-2010 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, General Education to Include Non-Academic Activities Outside the Classroom,1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, Jackson Committee,1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day,1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day,1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day,1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day,1998 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day,1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1992 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Photographs,1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,1988 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,1994 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,1998 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,1999 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,2001 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,2002 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 1, KCP College Day Visiting Professor,2003 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Minority Enrollment Goals,1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Minority Equity Plan,1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Minority Equity Plan,1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Multicultural Advisory Council,1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Multicultural Colloquia,2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Multicultural Education Center Staff Training,2007 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, NAACP,1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, NAACP: CMU Chapter,2006 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, National Rainbow Coalition,1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Office of Minority Affairs,1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, One Day,1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Personal and Institutional Factors Influencing CMU Students’ Attitudes About Native American Issues,2005 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Planning Goal 4: Global Education and Cultural Diversity at CMU,1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, POWER Workshop,2007 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, President’s Task Force on Minority Students Concerns,1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Previous Proposals, Multicultural Center,1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Proposal: American Indian Program,1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Proposal: Multicultural Center at CMU,1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Proposal: Restructuring of University to Enhance Diversity and Equity,1991 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Provost’s Seminar Series,2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Racism Hearings at CMU,1992 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: A Visit at CMU,1996 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: Diversity Issues and Awareness Council,1994 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: Internationalizing at CMU,1989 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: Internationalizing at CMU,1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: Military Science Committee,1991 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 2, Report: Multicultural Diversity Task Force,1988 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Report: Provost’s Task Force on the Women’s Center,1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Report: Public Hearings on Racism,1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Report: Sexual Harassment, Experiences of CMU Employees,1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Report: Study of Attitudes and Experiences of Undergraduates at CMU’s Mt. Pleasant Campus,1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Soup and Substance Fan: “The History Behind ‘Big Hats’ in the African American Tradition,2010 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Special Topics Course: “The Africans”,1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Unwritten Rules of Campus Communication,1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Winter Activities,1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Women’s Commission,1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 3, Women’s Institute,1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Affirmative Direction Newsletters,1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, American Indian Action Group Meeting: Agenda, Minutes, Goals, Native American Students, Report,1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Anishnaabe Culture and History: Beyond Stereotypes,2001 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Campus Climate Survey: American Indian Mascot Study, Memorandums,1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Center for Applied Research and Rural Studies, Chippewa Nickname,2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, “Chippewa” Nickname,2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Correspondence: Native American Symbols, Chippewa as Mascot,1989-2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Honors Program Senior Research Project: “Examining the Chippewa Nickname at CMU”,1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Michigan Civil Rights Commission Report on the Use of Nicknames, Logos, and Mascots Depicting Native American People,1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Addition Acc# 73681, Box 4, Miscellaneous: Chippewa as Symbol,1990, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)